Xiang (Emily) Zuo

220 Darryl Dr., Campbell, CA 95008, USA

+1 (408) 872-2860 | xiangzuo2012@gmail.com | in www.linkedin.com/in/xiangzuo

Summary

Extensive industrial machine learning analytic and engineering experience. Strong backgrounds of architect design in machine learning/deep learning enterprise products. Skilled in **natural language processing (NLP), large-scale systems, and database**. Technical leadership on managing multiple projects and defining technical direction of emerging AI market.

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Science, University of South Florida, Florida (USF)	2010 - 2016
M.S. in Computer Science, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), China	2006 - 2009
B.S. in Computer Science, Huazhong University of Science and Technology (HUST), China	2000 - 2004

Work Experience

Teradata Santa Clara, CA

Staff Machine Learning Engineer

March 2019 - Now ons (O&A) and SOL

- Lead a team to develop a customer-facing **TeraAnalyticChat** that enables AI-based **conversations** (**Q&A**) and **SQL query generation** in database system, empowering users to easily use in-database analytic functions, all via natural language (Azure Open AI and Cognitive Search)
- Build a Teradata ChatGPT-like model by fine-tuning the OpenLLaMA with synthetically-generated data using retrieval augmented generation (RAG) and a search engine, combined with public and employee-created data. Large language model (LLM) techniques like qLora, Adapter, PEFT are used to enhance tuning and memory efficiency (PyTorch, Huggingface)
- Develop COVID-19 Q&A system by using BERT, intent classification, arima and elastic search by Tensorflow
- Lead (researched, designed, and developed) the project of GLMNet and NaiveBayes, ZTest, FTest, Chisquare, ANOVA, KNN, VectorDistance, SMOTE on **MapReduce** framework of Teradata platform (C/C++)
- Coach new hires and serve as a core interviewer for technical hiring

Teradata Santa Clara, CA

Senior Machine Learning Engineer

Aug. 2016 - Feb. 2019

- Design and develop a suit of distributed machine-learning algorithms (e.g., XGBoost, Adaboost, Random Forest, TF-IDF, NaiveBayesTextClassifier, and Hashing Encodings) on MapReduce framework of Teradata Vantage (JAVA)
- Provide strong support for marketing, account, and professional service teams on solving all kinds of customers' issues
- Serve as **POC site manager** for enterprise customers including Verizon and AT&T

Distributed System & Social Computing Lab

University of South Florida

Research Assistant

Aug. 2010 - May. 2016

Design and implement algorithms and services for large-scale **social network** systems. Skills: distributed systems, characterization of social and peer-to-peer networks, **graph theory**, **data security**, and **cloud computing**

San Diego Supercomputer Center

University of California San Diego

Research Intern

Summer, 2014

Work on topics including big data computing, applied machine learning and statistical analysis of data using R

Human Computer Interaction Lab

Nokia Research Center

Research Intern

May - Aug. 2012

Implement a recommendation system based on user common contacts, similar interests, and physical encounters.

Skills

Machine Learning Tools and Libraries: PyTorch, Tensorflow, HuggingFace, LangChain, Scikit-learn

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C/C++, R, UNIX Shell
Application: MapReduce, GPU CUDA, ggplot

DBMS: Teradata Database, PostgreSQL
Tools: Vim, Bash, Docker, Kubernetes, Git

Honors Awards & Patents

"An Open-Source Alternative to ChatGPT", Teradata Hack Day 2nd Prize (2nd among 83)	June 2023
"Hyperparameter Tuner for Vantage Analytics", Teradata Hack Day 1st Prize (Top 1 among 60)	June 2021
"Hyper-Segment IDR", Teradata Patent	Dec 2020
"COVID-19 Q&A system based on BERT ", Finalist in Teradata Hack Day (5 among 50)	May 2020